All the yogas end up at the Union
of your being with your attention.
For example, you are listening to Me just now
and your attention is inside-out in the
sense that you are watching Me outside.
But if I say you that take your attention from outside
and put it inside from where you are listening to Me,
can you do it? – You can’t!
This attention goes outside of the human beings
and that is the problem that we
cannot take our attention inside.
That is the reason why our union
with our self is not established already.
And, it has to be established!
If you realise that there is someone
within us who is watching us all the time,
who is noticing everything that we do;
the one who is inside us and the one which looks outside
but we cannot go to that personality or that entity or
that being,
there is a gap between us and that personality.
That personality is called in
the various scriptures as Spirit, as Atma.
People have talked about it
and told that we have to manifest our Spirit.
Means our attention should become one with that Spirit.
It has been said by every scripture.
Everyone of them has talked about us,
that once our attention meets that spirit,
that is we are really ourselves, that Self,
then we are reborn and that is the self realisation.